Caroline Kays

P Bellingham, WA

Caroline.kays@live.com

+1(425)-305-8321

LinkedIn/carolinekays

Kays-c.com

SUMMARY

Innovative and eager Junior UX/UI Designer with 1 year of experience in project management and front-end design. Directed collaborative efforts and front-end design for a senior project at Western Washington University, leading to successful client satisfaction and timely delivery of project milestones. Seeking a <u>UX/UI</u> Designer position to enhance user experience and design innovative solutions through strong design and project management skills.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science | Western Washington University

September 2020 - December 2024, Bellingham, WA

Peer mentor to computer science pre-majors in the process of pursuing their degree, facilitator of weekly one-on-one meetings to provide guidance and motivation for their success in the department.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Project | Western Washington University

January 2024 - December 2024, Bellingham, WA

- Directed collaborative weekly meetings with teammates, checking individual progress, and tracking project deliverables.
- Led the front-end design of our project website, ensuring a polished and functional final product.
- o Facilitated meetings with our client, shared project progress, and ensured deliverables met the client's needs.

Social Media Manager | Ineffable Healing

August 2024 - December 2024, Bellingham, WA

- Expanded the business's digital presence and community engagement by launching new account platforms—to broaden audience reach.
- Managed and assisted with content creation, publishing across Instagram and YouTube.
- o Authored monthly newsletters to strengthen subscriber connection and drive engagement.

Undergraduate Research Assistant | Western Washington University

January 2023 - April 2024, Bellingham, WA

- Contributed to a collaborative research team developing a 3D virtual therapy world for online therapy sessions (for a local clinic) using Unity engine and C# scripting.
- Implemented VR features that enhanced user engagement and accessibility by developing various types of movement and intractability features.

SKILLS

- Technical Skills: Java, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, UI Design, Wireframing, Figma, Adobe, Unity, React.
- Hard Skills: User Research, Technical Writing, Agile Methodologies, Pair Programming, Code Reviews.
- Soft Skills: Communication, Collaboration, Team Synergy, Mentorship, Project Coordination, Leadership.